hello and a warm welcome to my youtube
channel where i share my analysis on
stocks and indexes purely from an
educational point of view now this video
is made on the insurance stocks keeping
in mind that the much-awaited ipo of lic
is coming out in march
now like all sectors we know that the
stocks of a particular sector will be it
auto be it energy be it
banking
or be it
infrastructure they tend to move in
tandem with each other of course they
sometimes one or outperforms the other
and one underperforms but more or less
the direction
is uh common for all the stocks
time to time large capsule outperform
small and vice versa but similarly the
same state happens in the case of
insurance stocks the big four names like
hdfc life icici lombard icici prudential
and sbi life now you know we all know
that this ipo has been much talked about
and
you know it's uh it was more or less
known in public circles and all that it
would be coming in the month of march
but it's the timing of the ipo right now
which
is
what people are going to talk about uh
first the correction which has been
happening in our markets both large cap
and mid cap and small cap since
october
2021 and the other is the recent
russian ukrainian crisis which has
actually spooked all markets now
let's have a you know if smart money
were to invest its uh
money in the insurance stocks so it will
naturally like uh
compare
the price the valuation the
technicals of the peer companies which
are there currently listed in our
markets now of course there is no doubt
that lic is the undisputed
market leader it has the giant share in
the market and apart from that it's got
into
a lot of assets it invests in the market
in a very big manner but still the
insurance companies talk start money
will try to analyze them and try to
compare
how are things keeping up with those
socks now in this video i have no i
would like to share with you all
my
analysis based on ichimoku and harmonic
patterns on the four large players that
is hdfc life icici lombard icsa
prudential and sbi
life but let's start with
hdfc
live
insurance company now
we can see out here in the monthly chart
that the stock
started its correction in september 2021
that's overall market correction started
mid
october to early november around diwali
but this one started uh much earlier
from there and ever since then
has corrected to 50
of its covered rally that rally which
started at 350 odd went up to
775 is now at the 50 replacement range
which is also the ichimoku monthly
baseline support now usually smart money
when it comes to investments looks at
such opportunities to add on dips you
know or buy the dip these are strong
support levels which we have seen
regularly among stocks which have got
strong potential of upside where the
growth story is intact such
opportunities don't go begging people
tend to buy them
for investment point of view or for
decent returns from these
from the baseline support level now
let's have a look at what the
weekly is uh
showing us out here now the weekly the
interesting fact about it is that the
stock
every time it
went and tested its
upper trend line it would correct from
there it could start doing a correction
from this level uh first one came in may
2018 then came in uh october 2 september
october 2020 then again in
may of 2021 and the final one in
september so we know that this was the
resistance every time it plopped down
from there apart from that
the stock
made a
head and shoulder breakdown
in the month of uh
november and towards november end it
gave a head and shoulder breakdown which
we can see out here
so this was the
shoulder
the head
and this was the other shoulder so the
breakdown came and the breakdown has now
completed its full target out here at
the bearish target for the
breakdown has been completely done with
apart from that we can also see an
ichimoku support out here which
coincides
with the
the monthly support at 550.
apart from that
we also
can see out here that you know the stock
has made
bullish
harmonic
titan
in case it does a retest of its
lows which was made out here so this is
a bullish harmonic alt sharp
which is
done out here which is again suggesting
a good
possibility of
so
now in case it does the there is a good
support sitting out here around
530 35 or 11 in case the test is happens
and bounces back so overall the stock is
near major support
zones now that's the good thing about it
from an investing point of view let's
have a look at
where is the current resistance in it
the resistance for the stock is
initially at
580 and then at 600. once it takes out
these two levels it could go and you
know retest 650 to 670 in case we
consider this just as a bounce keeping
in mind the overall market condition and
the
ipo issue where you know
valuations of peer companies will also
be looked at in you know with scrutiny
and all so
good opportunity of you know this level
doing
uh a decent bounce back from you now
let's have a look at the next one which
is ic ici
lombard general insurance company now
here also we can see in the monthly
chart the stock has
come down
from the
september same scenario from september
the correction started earlier on and
now we have a sharp pull down which has
come again to the monthly base support
another stock which is respecting the
monthly base support
lying out here you know it's come out
here you saw the bounce back from 1240
a couple of days back
and uh
yeah so
in in from that sense it set a fantastic
money buying opportunity value buying
would be absorbed at that level now
interestingly in the
weekly it has made not one but two
bullish harmonic patterns out here the
first one
is a
deep crab
which was formed and at the same time
apa along with the deep crab
just expand it a bit
yeah along with the deep crab we can
also see
a bullish
alt sharp formation in the stock which
has taken place
out here
right at the same level
so
not one but two harmonic bullish
harmonic patterns along with
a monthly ichimoku support suggesting
that this could do a good bounce back if
not a reversal in that case so
it's got fantastic support lying at 225
odd levels 200 125 would be fantastic
support level while it's got a
resistance now at 1290 starts sustaining
above 1290 the stock could do 1400 to
1500 in a in the case of a bounce
reversal would be much bigger of course
so overall
a
very good scenario out here
suggesting
a move on the upside in the case of
icici lombard now let's have a look at
icici prudential
the other arm of icl says insurance
business now icci prudential has a
bearish c-clamp in the monthly time
frame and it's got a suggested target of
around 475
to 480 again a stock which started its
correction in september very all the
companies like i said they tend to move
together but some outperform the other
some underperformed so similarly
this one also has not seen any pullback
just apart from the
january doji candle long like dooji
candle out here so we have 475 480 as a
zone which could
be a fantastic level where smart money
would again start looking at it which is
not very far from smart money
perspective it's not very fun now let's
have a look at what the weekly is doing
for us
the weekly is again approaching a
fantastic support level of similarly 470
to 65 to 470 which is also uh
in line with the
weekly
with the monthly support so both time
higher time frames i've got
people you know the smart money which
would be looking to must have already
started adding or will look to add
more aggressively at those
levels now the resistance for the stock
is at
510 odd level sustaining above 510
would stake that stock back if not for a
major
pullback then at least a bounce back
till 550
in this case
so uh
510 immediate resistance 475
immediate support today was a gap down
like most of the market this one has not
yet covered its gap apart you know index
did it but this one did not do it so
above the gap would be probably look at
you know tested interest will come into
the
smart money would be looking at it else
they would be waiting uh around this
zone to come to enter the stock out
there so again another insurance company
which is not yet gone to its major
support not necessary that the stock
will go and absolutely test it but in
case it does that's the level to look
forward to of 470 or level 75 otherwise
above 510 the stock could start its
upward bounds at least in 550
if if it's not a major reversal that we
are looking out here currently you know
keeping in mind the global scenario and
our overall market correction since
october now finally for the last one in
alphabetical order sbi life
sbi life has uh
monthly is a huge bearish engulfing
candle and just with uh
you know couple of more days left for
the monthly
candle to end this could become a black
maru bozo candle also puzzle candle
which is uh from a stand-alone point of
view looks quite bearish compared to the
other stocks were but there's a reason
behind that why
apart from the other insurance company
why does the sbi life monthly candle
look so bearish you know if we go back
to
icsa credential or we go back to
lombard for that matter or hdfc this one
in particular looks quite
uh severe in size the reason behind that
is that if you look at the weekly
uh
set up for this one this one topped up
in
a month later in october first of all
and after a small drift down
to its baseline support it managed to do
a bounce back and you know just about
tested to be high
and turned around from there so this
testing took place in mid-jan just a
month back so hence the catch-up
by
sbi life with the other insurance
companies makes this monthly candle look
quite severe compared to the other
stocks because uh it was outperforming
the three of them so
it it's made up and now join and earn
now coming back to the analysis at the
current juncture uh today is just
tuesday so too early to say whether this
will turn out to be a bearish single
thing or a black mobuzu here also but
what is more important is that the stock
is now
at a solid ichimoku
cloud support okay that's that's usually
where we see bounces coming from in
stocks and uh
today's
reversal is also like an inverted hammer
out here which was like in like in the
case of most stocks have not broken
their 15th uh
february or 14 feb lows and held on to
it today but that's too early to say
whether this is a confirmed reversal
happening out there that this is like a
you know short-term head or is this a
double bottom
scenario kind of seen out here or triple
bottom whatever we want to call it but
the scene is that it's at that weekly
support so the stock
could uh
witness some kind of
traction in it if it can survive
right now you know about
1125 that would be interesting to watch
if it can do that then it could bounce
back to
1150 to 1175
in a bounce back stage reversal would be
much bigger but overall 1175 would be a
bigger resistance approaching it in the
coming weeks in that order so all in all
all the insurance companies are
bouncing from a support or
up at a support right now which suggests
that
they might pause their fall if not
bounce or reverse back from here
whether it is because of global markets
or their correction is over or it's the
lic ipo but it's an area where smart
money will definitely be looking at it
as an attractive level entry in it i
hope this video is of help to you all
and
if you like the video please do not
forget to like share
the video and subscribe to the channel a
disclaimer before we end
please do not consider any of these as a
trading advice or an investing advice
please do your research thoroughly and
carefully before coming to a final
conclusion in it until then happy
investing everyone bye